SAMEEHA RAHMAN

Colombo, Sri Lanka +94766369906 rahman.sameeha@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sameeha-rahman samsam-026.github.io github.com/samsam-026

FRONT END DEVELOPER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

A degree-educated developer with two academic qualifications in the field, with working knowledge in many web and hybrid mobile technologies, such as React.js, Angular, React Native and Flutter. An engineer who stays up to date on recent technologies and inventions in the fields of science and technology, who constantly revises software best practices and user experience guidelines. A blogger at two popular online news platforms, with articles in multiple technical topics. An award-winning event organizer of hackathons, with experience in chairing tech conferences.

EDUCATION

M. Sc. Computer Science | Queen Mary University of London (Sept. 2020 – Present) Currently following a 2-year part-time Master of Science in Computer Science, studying Functional Programming, Bayesian Decision and Risk Analysis, Mobile Services and Design for Human Interaction.

B. Eng. Software Engineering | University of Westminster (Sept. 2016 – July 2020)Awarded **First Class Honours** in the 4-year Software Engineering Course offered by the University of Westminster, UK, in partnership with the Informatics Institute of Technology, Sri Lanka.

Bachelor Diploma as Frontend Developer | OpenClassrooms (Sept. 2019 – May 2020) OpenClassrooms is Europe's largest online education platform recognized as a higher education institution. The course is project-driven, focusing on putting concepts into practice. It connects students with industry professionals for 1 to 1 mentorship on a weekly basis. Completed all 9 projects ranging from a WordPress application, an HTML-based game, to a React.js restaurant review website.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer | Switchd Ltd. (Sept. 2020 – Present)

Implemented the redesign of the company product website, Switchd, and the new green product, MakeMyHouseGreen, that provides bespoke green product quotes to homeowners.

Technology: HTML, CSS, JS, PHP React.js, Next.js, SQL.

Freelancer | Capitol Overseas Courier Service (Pvt.) Ltd. (June 2017 – Aug. 2020)

Designed and implemented the company website and invoicing and internal operation systems using ASP.NET Core technologies. Redesigned old MSSQL database to a smaller, less redundant set of tables.

Technology: Classic ASP, Visual Basic, MSSQL, ASP .NET Core, React.js.

Software Engineering Intern | 99x Technology (Pvt.) Ltd. (July 2018 – July 2019)

Designed and implemented the updated mobile app UI designs. Principal Engineer of company open-source project first-born, a React Native UI Component Library and Framework. Created the second React Native mobile app skeleton with Redux and navigation. Setup the development pipeline using Jenkins to run Jest unit tests before merging branches.

Technology: React Native, Java, Node.js, MSSQL, Flutter.

SKILLS

- o Great team worker and organizer with good communication skills.
- O Skilled in hybrid mobile technology, like React Native and Flutter, and created a React-Native UI component Library first-born.
- o Delivers work that is centred in User Experience (UX) guidelines.
- o Trained in web technologies and popular frameworks React.js and Angular.

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, React.js, React Native, Flutter, Ionic, Angular, Typescript, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, MSSQL, Firebase, ASP.NET, C#, Jest, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Git.

ACTIVITIES

Projects

Developer | first-born (2019)

A React Native UI framework consisting of inbuilt components developed using Atomic design, with over 2000 downloads and 200 stars on GitHub. This highly customizable library allows UI components to render separately according to the underlying platform, following platform UX guidelines, reducing the work of front-end developers.

Technology: React Native, Jest, ESLint.

Volunteering

Project Secretary | CodeSprint 3.0 Startup Battle (Dec. 2017 – March 2018)

Organized a month-long accelerator for start-ups created by University students in Sri Lanka, to pitch to investors and get funding for their technological solutions. Won Best Student Branch Activity at the 2018 IEEE Congress, Sri Lanka.

Certifications

Google Mobile Sites (2018 – 2019)

EF Standard English Test (C1 Advanced) (2016)

Competitions

Runner-Up | JumpStart - Achievers Lanka Business School (Dec. 2017)

Finalist: 4th | CIMA Launch Pad – CIMA (Nov. 2017)

Runner-Up | TadHack - hSenid Mobile (Oct. 2017)

Runner-Up | BeThem Challenge – 99X Technology (Dec. 2016)

REFERENCES

Available on request.